Among your acquaintances there are many
Среди ваших Знакомых много есть те
who died in the war Yes unfortunately there
которые погибли на войне Да к сожалению
are yes How many
есть есть Сколько
approximately Oh I don't even know if I should
приблизительно О я даже не знаю стоит ли
tell you eight
вам говорить восемь
people is a lot for acquaintances Yes
человек это много как для знакомых Да
it's a
это
lot
много
Hello Hello
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
where are you from I'm from Russia and you Yes I see And what
откуда Я из России а вы Да я вижу А
city are you not Russian
город какой выж не русский
so Yash Korala does anything tell you
так Яш корала что-нибудь вам говорит
Yes The
Да
Republic of Mari
Республика Марий
L can't be you are the first person
л не может быть вы первый человек
who knows where it is this is more I will say
который знает где это это больше я скажу
my father was born in the Mari
у меня отец родился в марийской
ASSR in the suburbs of
АССР в пригороде
Shkara I am half Mari you are in Israel
шкара я мариец наполовину вы в Израиле
yes
да
m you are in Israel yes Yes yes this is the flag of
м вы в Израиле да Да да это флаг
Israel no behind it is the EU flag I say
Израиля нет сзади Это флаг ЕС Я говорю у
you have an Israel plaque
вас плашка Израиль стоит
where Well here at the bottom this one is from Israel
где Ну вот внизу этот на зна из Израиля
yes A Wow It turns out I have Mom
да А Ничего себе У меня получается Мама
oh father is Mari from Vesh Korol And my mother is
ой отец мариец из веш Корол А мама
Jewish, she was from Berdichev and I left for
еврейка была из Бердичева и я выехал в
Israel then by the way I am in Hai
Израиль потом я кстати т в Хай
about a hundred people who come from or have
около сотни людей которые родом из или
roots in the Mari SSR And we have yes
корнями из марийской ССР Вот и у нас да
in Haifa We have yes
в Хайфе У нас есть да
uh some people are called the
ээ часть людей называется
society of the Mari L community
общество землячество Марии Л
it is called in Israel or something Yes in
называется это в Израиле что ли Да в
Haifa it's amazing I'm just in general  I'm really
Хайфе удивительно я прям вообще я прям
surprised no
удивлён нет
one asks just no one knows
кто не спрашивает просто никто не знает
even from Russia who asks there doesn't
даже вот из России кто спрашивает там не
know where it is and all or Russians too
знает где это и всё чи россияне тоже
I say the Volga region people just like that with their
я говоришь Поволжье люди просто вот так
eyes wide open
вот глаза вытаращив
half Mari they like who are Jews still
наполовину мариец они типа кто евреи ещё
understand And Mari I say this is an
понимают А мариец я говорю это в
indigenous people in the Russian Federation
Российской Федерации коренной народ
the Republic of Mari e I tell them the
Республика Мари е ж я им рассказываю
story there were Russian-Mari wars
историю там русско-марийский войны были
yes that is Moscow didn't immediately capture
да то есть Москва ж не сразу захватила
us so it was there for hundreds of years war
нас так она там сотни лет война была
then when it captured then part of the Mari
потом когда захватила то часть марийцев
moved to the Grand Duchy
переселилась в Великое княжество
of Lithuania you know this
Литовское знаете эту ж
story Well we studied something But it was
историю Ну мы что-то изучали Но это было
a long time ago I'm already just an old man
очень давно я уже просто старый человек
you can say sk I'm already 40 we are
можно сказать ском лет мне уже 40 мы
now more absorbed in family work
сейчас поглощены больше семьёй работой
everything else
всем остальным
this year will be 44 as it were but I
в этом году уже 44 как бы будет но я как
like in Haifa we have more
бы у нас в Хайфе больше есть
opportunities to devote ourselves there to something
возможности посвятить себя там чему-то
spiritual because well as the standard of
духовному потому что ну как бы уровень
living is better than in Russia after all
жизни лучше чем в России всё-таки
Yeah And you left on repatriation yes yes on
Угу А вы уехали по репатриации да да по
repatriation at  I had the opportunity, as
репатриации у меня была возможность как
I thought, either to go to my father's homeland
бы я думал или поехать на родину к отцу
in the scale Yes there Well to Mariel or to go
в шкалу Да туда Ну в мариел либо поехать
to my mother's homeland Well of course I compared
на про Родину мамы Ну конечно сравнил
Yeshko and Haifa and thought that Haifa would be
Ешко и Хайфу и думал что Хайфа будет
somehow
как-то
better and they didn't move dad or something dad
получше а папу не перевезли что ли папа
also came yes Well then Well here's the family
тоже приехал да А ну тогда Ну вот семья
reunite it turns out Mom
вос соедини получается Мама
received citizenship in Israel Yes and
как получила гражданство в Израиле Да и
dad with her because he is registered with her
папа с ней потому что он расписан с ней
and I As mom's son also like everything is
и я Как мамин сын тоже типа всё
clear It's clear very interesting Of course
и ясно Ясно очень интересно Конечно у
how you live now lie
вас как вы сейчас жите ври
yes Well you can say next to Mariel but
да Ну можно сказать рядом с марил но у
my work is periodically connected with
меня периодически работа связана с
a trip to the city but look how with the
поездкой в город а вот смотри как с
language because in our Haifa in
языком потому что вот в нашем Хайфе в
our Mari society only two
нашем обществе марийцев только двое
people understand the Mari language For
человек понимают Марийский язык Я
example I don't know many unfortunately yes
например не знаю многие не сожалению да
I will tell you so unfortunately
я вам скажу так к сожалению у
our language is slowly
нас язык потихонечку он как бы
dissolving That is of course it's a pity
растворяется То есть это конечно жалко
but Night on the one hand they began to
но Ноча с одной стороны начали как будто
revive various there these are held Well
возрождать различные там эти проходят Ну
like language festivals festivals of folk
как фестивали языка фестивали народных
costumes that is well there is such a thing
костюмов то есть ну вот такое
Well fie schools  No, I don't have a burning
есть Ну фие школ Да не горит Не горит
desire to speak my native language, but
желанием говорить на родном языке но
some speak it very well. Well, they
некоторые говорят очень даже хорошо Ну
don't speak their native language because there's
не говорят на родном языке потому что
no point. Yes, because Russia, like
нет смысла Да потому что Россия как
schools only in Russian, universities in
школы только на русском университеты на
Russian, it turns out, like Mari, it's
русском получается как бы марийски это
like the language of the Indians.
как язык индейцев сделали
No, no. The Mari language is taught in schools.
нет нет Марийский язык в школах
It's just not that popular
преподают Просто он не так популярен
because everyone still speaks Yes, but
потому что все вс-таки общаются на Да но
it's taught As if it were a foreign language
его преподают Как как будто иностранный
twice a week. And all the subjects are not in
два раза в неделю А все предметы Не на
Mari but in
марийском а на
Russian. And young people still
русском Да и молодёжь всё равно
strive, let's say, to leave,
стремится как бы ну скажем так уехать
you know. That is, it seems to them that they
понимаете То есть у них им кажется что
have more opportunities. Well,
больше есть возможности Ну вот у нас
Kazan is not far from here. Dato narot na serato.
Казань недалеко Дато нарот на серато
Moscow
Москва столетиями
has been sucking out St. Petersburg for centuries, and now it turns out that
высасывает и как сейчас тоже получается
the Mari are also what are we, uh, our people
марийцы мы что там ээ наш народ
are dissolving, now the resources are being taken away,
растворяется сейчас ресурсы забирают это
Muscovites don't even know where. This is not in
москвичи даже не знают где-то Это ни это
the world, you know. Yes, no one knows, no one
мира понимаете да никто не знает никто
knows, 30 km away from Moscow, they
не знает отъе на 30 кмет от Москвы они
don't know what the Volga region is, they don't know what
не знают что такое поволжя они не знают
Kazan is, they don't know what st is
что такое Казань не знают что такое сть
for them.  these are countries with
для них это вские дае страны с
unknown times such people are overloaded with
неизвестными время такое люди загру
work people are busy earning
работой люди загружены зарабатываем
money that is some people are just
денег то есть часть людей просто
scared of what is happening around
напугана тем что вокруг происходит
so unfortunately for now this is the
поэтому к сожалению пока Вот такая
situation I think the light at the end of the tunnel will
обстановочка я думаю свет конце тоннеля
appear sooner or later and
рано или поздно появится и
Grozny Yes this is good this
Грозный Да это хорошо Это
means the Russian Federation is approaching
значит Российская Федерация близится к
its collapse it is the same as it was in
своему распаду это также как было в 1917
1917 yes there in Petrograd everyone was sitting
году да там эти в Петрограде Все сидели
and having a good time and then Hop and the Empire fell apart
да мажорчик да а потом Гоп и развалилась
also in Perm in Moscow the
Империя также в дено Перм году в Москве
Communist Party was bathing in milk there and people
компартия купалась там в молоке а люди
in the regions were starving in fact there was no meat
по регионах голодали по сути мяса не
That's all the same and here now Moscow
было Вот и вс так и тут сечас Москва
I don't believe because if we are going to separate
я не верю потому что Если уж отделяться
then everyone should separate everyone should not
то должны отделиться все все не
separate if let's say one republic
отделяться если допустим одна республика
separates you me Sorry who
отделится вы меня Извините таки кто её
recognizes it in the world you understand not the same yes that
признает в мире понимаете не тоже да вот
's how it turns out when in ninety-
это так как получается когда В девяносто
second
втором
Tatarstan
Татарстан
separated Chechnya Ingushetia you see how
отделился Чечня Ингушетия видите как бы
few of them there were but now it is shaking very
их было мало но сейчас шатается очень
well Nede Tatarstan not  Tatarstan
хорошо Неде Татарстан не Татарстан
separated, it voted for independence, there
отделял он проголосовал за независимость
was a referendum and in December of the year
был референдум и в дено вром году
Tatarstan did not sign this
Татарстан не подписал этот как он
federal treaty, they agreed on everything, no
федеральный договор обо всём договорился
one separated there, unfortunately, this is
там никто не отделял к сожалению это
just a common opinion that, well, it
просто распространённое мнение что ну
separated, but in fact, there was no
отделился Но на самом деле никакого
separation, everything was quick, there was
отделения там всё быстренько вот была
an attempt to separate in Chechnya, if you remember,
попытка отделения у Чечни если помните
they had such a president, Aslan Maskhadov,
был у них такой президент Аслан Масхадов
they formed a government, something
там сформировали правительство что-то у
seemed to work out for them there, but
них там даже будто бы получалось но
again, the federal NT
опять-таки федеральный НТ
restored all this to constitutional
всё это восстановил конституционный
order. Well, you see now, now The fact is
порядок Ну сейчас видите сейчас Дело в
that Russia, as an Empire, rests on the
том что Россия как Империя держится на
security forces and now the security
силовых структурах и сейчас силовой
apparatus of the Russian Federation is dying
аппарат Российской Федерации он умирает
in Ukraine. Yes, it is still very much
в Украине Да всё-таки он очень сильно
undermined and it seems to me that this will bear very
подорван и мне кажется это даст очень
great fruit in many regions,
большие свои плоды во многих регионах
discontent with the central government is growing.
растёт недовольство Центральной властью
So we will see. I still believe
Так что будем посмотреть Я всё-таки верю
that
что
our peoples, who were once
наши народы которые когда-то были
submissive to Moscow, will gain independence.
покорны Москвой обретут независимость
Everything can be like this, the situation. Believe me,
Все может быть и так ситуация Повер
you know, like the Soviet Union. I always
знаете как Советский Союз Я вот всегда
look at who thought. In 1991
смотрю кто думал В девяносто первом году
or in 1990, that the Soviet Union
или в девяностом что Советский Союз
will fall apart and then the GKChP and in 3
развалится а потом Гоп гкчп и через 3
days the Soviet Union will be gone,
дня нету Советского Союза
that's it, well, to be honest,
всё ну честно говоря вот отделились
Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, Kazakhstan separated. Well,
Узбекистан Таджикистан Казахстан Да вот
I also go to Kazakhstan for work, yes. Well, to be
я в Казахстан тоже по работе езжу да Ну
honest, I'll tell you. Besides the fact that there
честно я вам скажу Кроме того что там
tenge is worth 100 rubles instead of 100 rubles, everything else is
тенге вме 100 рублей там всё остальное
like, everything is
как бы всё
Russian, everything is
российское вообще всё
Russian, Kyrgyzstan, gasoline, Russian
Российская Киргизия бензин Российский
product, Russian. So, here, it's like,
продукт российские Так что тут как бы
who separated where, to be honest, don't
кто куда отделился честно говоря не
look, the thing is, the thing is, that's the
смотри дело в том дело в том что тут вот
problem. The problem is that Moscow,
в чём проблема Проблема в том что Москва
as an Empire, tied itself to the entire economy of the colonies.
как Империя она всю экономику колоний
I have friends in Ukraine.
подвязалася меня знакомые в Украине есть
Yes, it separated, but the industry, the
Да она отделилась но промышленность
economy was very closely tied to
экономика очень сильно связана была с
Russia, also because, well, this is the Soviet Union,
Россией ещё потому что ну это Советская
this economic Web, and the way out of
вот эта Паутина экономическая и выход из
this process is long. Ukraine has already
этого процесса он долгий Украина уже
left. Yes, Ukraine has completely integrated into the
вышла да Украина полностью интегри уже в
Western world. Everything is with Russia. It broke up. For
Западный мир всё с Россией Она порвала А
example, this process has
например у Казахстана Узбекистана
been going on longer for Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, Kyrgyzstan,
Таджикистана Кыргызстана дольше идёт
it's
этот процесс это
natural. It's been going on for 50 years. Well,
природно он уже 50 лет идт Ну
yes. There's no end in sight. It
да Что конца края не видать не Мне
seems to me that Russia will most likely not
кажется скорее всего Россия не
fall apart. Russia will most likely just
развалится Россия скорее всего просто
follow the path of Europe. That is, it will be.
пойдёт по пути Европы То есть это будет
small states in a common area Well,
маленькие государства в общей зоне Ну
like Schengen, something like that, maybe also
как Шенген типа того вот может быть тоже
with the Federal Center, but already somehow like
с Федеральным центром но уже как-то вот
that, but I don't believe in the Collapse of Russia at
вот так вот но в Развал России я не верю
all That is, on the contrary,
от слова совсем То есть тут наоборот
everyone is saying The war began in Russia
вот все говорят Война началась в россие
under sanctions My friends, you will forgive me of course,
под санкциями Друзья мои вы меня конечно
yes You want Ione, you want BMW, you want You
извините да Хочешь ione хочеш BMW хочешь
understand, any equipment, any technology
Понимаешь любая аппаратура любая техника
So Where are these, but it is more expensive But it is
Так что Куда эти но она дороже Но она
more expensive Well, and salaries are still
дороже Ну так и зарплату всё равно
being raised So nothing has really
поднимают Так что особо ничего не
changed, no, if you look at it in
поменялось не не если смотреть в
dollar terms, Russians have become poorer,
долларом эквиваленте беднее стали
salaries, prices have risen more
россияне зарплаты цены поднялись больше
than salaries, he has already made a mortgage by 23% or 22
чем зарплаты он ипотеку уже 23% или 22
Who is already taking it? And here there
сделали Кто её уже берёт всё А здесь
are some interesting schemes What For
есть кое-какие схемы интересные Какие
example, you work for some
Ну например вы работаете на какую-то
organization, they give you an apartment, you
организацию они вам дают квартиру вы
just slowly
просто её потихоньку
bathe in it I say this It's just a transitional
купаетесь Я говорю это Просто переходный
process, in theory, it has
процесс он на жизнь по идее он вообще
not affected life at all And who do you
никак не повлиял абсолютно вот А вы кем
work for? I am a driver, a driver, you can
работаете Я водитель водитель можно
say, uh Well, as we have such a very popular
сказать ээ Ну как у нас очень популярна
topic now, we carry spare parts  eh that
сейчас такая тема мы возим запчасти э то
is well in the morning eh roughly speaking we collect
есть ну с утра э грубо говоря собираем
from the warehouse we deliver to places and then
со склада развозим по местам и потом вот
on this topic now this work
на этой теме сейчас эта работа очень
has become very popular that is just can't
популярная стала вот то есть прямо не
fight back That's how things are
отбиться Вот такие вот дела
Cool yes yes yes So everyone is saying the
Прикольно да да да Так что все говорят
same thing that the war will end Russia will
тоже вот война закончится Россия будет
pay reparations I beg you no one
платить репарации Я вас умоляю никто
will pay anything Believe me I
ничего платить не будет Поверьте мне я
know Russia No one will pay anything
знаю Россию Никто ничего платить
no the question of reparations It's not a question
нетс вопрос репараций Это не вопрос
of voluntariness yes that is Russia
добровольности да то есть вот у России
has confiscated assets abroad so
конфискованные активы за рубежом так
reparations to Ukraine will be paid from
репарации Украине будут выплачиваться из
confiscated Russian assets in the
конфискованных российских активов в
modern world everything
современном мире всё просто
is done simply this money will not be enough even for and
делается этих денег не хватит даже на а
moreover on the way to Ukraine this
более того по дороге вот в Украину эти
money also like this in different directions
деньги ещё вот так вот в разные стороны
in short they climb look The thing is that
короче лезут смотри Дело в том что
look Europe and the
смотрите Европа и
USA are interested in pulling
США заинтересованы в том чтобы стягивает
reparations from Russia that's all because
с России репарации вот и всё потому что
eh Europe and the USA will also have something from this
э Европа и США будут тоже с этого иметь
so everything will be very simple yes they
так что всё будет очень просто да
are being looked at they are being conducted on trade
ведутся смотрите ведутся все на торговлю
with Russia duties reparations and
с Россией ведутся пошлины репараций и
that's all Well that means China Iran and as if this is an
всё Ну значит Китай Иран и как бы это
even greater confrontation here it
ещё большее противостояние тут уже
will not be fun for anyone it seems to me no
весело никому не будет мне кажется не
What And why does China need Russia, look,
Какое А зачем Китаю Россия смотрите у
China's trade turnover with Russia is 2% of the
Китая с Россией товарооборот 2%
Chinese economy, the US has something like
китайской экономики у США там что-то
30%, they'll still find some way out,
30% всё равно найдут какой-то выход
you know, they'll never give up,
понимаете эти не сдадутся никогда
never, never, who asks them what they said,
никогда Да кто их спрашивает что говорил
well, here we go again, yes, I
ну вот опять-таки да Я вот в этом году
went to Africa this year, for example,
ездил допустим в Африку
Yes, everything is available, everything is there, there are
Да всё доступно всё есть Доллары
no problems at all, changing dollars,
поменять вообще никаких
planes are flying, everything is fine,
проблем самолёты летают всё нормально
as
как бы
if, then probably the whole world should
это уж тогда наверное весь мир должен
just, you know, put up a wall around Russia
просто знаете стену вокруг России
and really, then
поставить и действительно там вот тогда
something can change there, But no,
может что-то поменять А так нет
parallel imports, shadow trade, all
параллельный импорт теневая торговля всё
this will always be, it has been And then gas is
это будет всегда было Да и потом газ же
still being pumped into Europe, money is still being pumped into it,
в Европу всё равно гонят денежки за это
Ukraine gets it, as if they,
то всё равно Украина получает как бы они
of course, say, we don't Where is gas going to Europe,
конечно Говорят мы не Где в газ в Европу
everything from the first, from January 1, no gas from
всё с перво с 1 января никакой газ из
Russia to Europe goes through Ukraine,
России в Европу не идёт через Украину
everything, the contract has expired and that's it
всё контракт закончился и всё
I have friends who are just on
У меня есть знакомые которые как раз на
this pipeline from our side, here is the gas
этой трубе с нашей стороны вот газ
that is pumped in, they are sitting and counting
который загоняется вот они сидят считают
How much gas went there, again, again
Сколько газа туда ушло ещё раз ещё раз
Until Until the twenty-fifth year there was a contract, yes,
До До двадцать пятого года контракт был
everything since the twenty-fifth year there is
да всё с двадцать пятого года контракт
no contract  spilled that why this Orban and
не пролили то что почему этот орбан и
Fitz are squeaking Slovakia still isn't getting
фиц пищат Словакию всё не поступает
Russian gas through Ukraine isn't going they
российский газ через Украину не идёт
closed I don't know I just see that everything is
закрыли не знаю я только вижу что всё
coming fine everything is no longer going
прекрасно поступает всё всё уже не ходит
as there was an agreement because European
как договор был потому что европейским
partners had to supply yes Everything
партнёрам надо было поставлять да Всё
now Well maybe maybe Well
теперь Ну может быть может быть Ну
believe me nothing
поверьте у простых крестьян ничего не
has changed at all absolutely for the simple peasants There is a Master yes no no one gives a damn about the
изменилось вообще абсолютно Барин есть
Master either everyone
да нет на Барина тоже всем плевать всех
is only interested in earning money and having
интересует только заработок и где-нибудь
a good rest somewhere Master is not a Master no one cares at all it's
хорошенечко отдохнуть Барин не Барин
cool like
прикольно такая
that so whatever Europe wants
вот так что что бы там Европа не хотела
unfortunately their plans are not coming true yet
к сожалению их планы пока не сбываются
maybe fortunately the devil
может и к счастью чёрт её
knows And what do you think How long will all this
знает А как вы считаете Долго ещё это
be oh I hope this year it will
будет ой я уж надеюсь в этом году это
all end God willing because in
всё закончится дай Бог потому что с на
fact I can't even imagine
деле я даже не представляю У меня честно
I can honestly tell you yes please Ulko
я вам скажу да вы меня пожалуйста улько
Don't scold me It seems to me that up there
Не ругайте Мне кажется там наверху
in my opinion they have already agreed on everything it's
по-моему уже обо всём договорились
just that now this process is underway it's just
просто сейчас это идёт процесс просто
quietly letting it go
спускает тихонечко на тормоза
Uh-huh one and everyone is shaking hands with each other as
Угу один же все другу же руку жмут как
if you understand one and  who shakes Putin's
бы понимаете один а кто кто Путину жмёт
hand Well, there are all sorts of summits there
руку Ну есть же на всякие саммиты там
BRICS, all this, all the same,
Брикс вот это вот всё как бы всё равно
it all works, whoever is at the BRICS summit
это всё работает та кто на саммите Брикс
Who was there, just these couple of friends of
Кто был только короче эти пару друзей
Russia and that's it
России и всё
Well, who shakes Putin's
Ну кто Путину жмёт
hand
руку
Well,
Ну
the CIS is not for Europe, it's unshakable for
СНГ не для Европы он нерукопожатные для
America, not for Ukraine, not
Америки не для Украины не
the OTC Well, why are you so categorical, it's
ОТС Ну что Вы прям так категорично тут
a matter of money, you know, they may not
дело в деньгах понимаете они могут на
shake hands in public, of course, but
публику конечно руки не жать но по
they can always come to an agreement over the phone Orban
телефону они всегда договорятся орбан
constantly calls Putin, there's someone
постоянно звонит Путину там е кто-то
calling Putin, Putin calls somewhere That's
звонит Путину Путин куда-то звонит Вот
how, in short, a foreigner,
так вот короче иностран
that summer we were in Kazan, I was just
ста тем летом мы были в Казани я просто
stunned, they have the Kazan River
офигел у них есть Казанский Речной
Station, it's all packed with Japanese, it's all
вокзал весь забит японцами просто весь
refusal, these Japanese grannies with
отказу вот эти вот бабушки японки с
cameras, running around taking pictures,
фотоаппаратами бегают всё фотографируют
what sanctions, I do
Какие санкции что
n't know at all,
вообще не знаю
damn, I can't see these
блин что-то не видать этих
San
Сан во
I looked What's wrong with Ukraine
Я смотрел Что из-за того что Украина
knocking out
выбивает своими беспилотниками
oil refineries in Russia with its drones,
нефтеперерабатывающие заводы в России да
what's wrong with gasoline, some kind of
что там что-то с бензином какие-то
interruption, prices are rising, what's the price there, in short
перебой цены растут что там цена короче
for gasoline if you take ninety-second
на бензин если брать девяносто второй
it is 52 regular 54 in short it is like with
это 52 обычный 54 короче это типа с
additives ninety-fifth the price reaches
присадками девяносто пятый доходит цена
6 if with additives But again
до 6 если с присадками Но опять-таки
it has become more expensive or I know how much it is becoming more expensive for you
это подорожало или яже зна сколько у вас
no one pays attention to it anymore it is
ы дорожает на это уже никто внимания не
that before the war they are
обращает оно что до войны
expensive it comes out to this
дорожат выходит вот в этот вот как бы
level and people still Well how do they
уровень и люди всё равно Ну как также
live Listen but among your
живут Слушайте а вот Среди ваших
acquaintances there are many who died
Знакомых много есть те которые погибли
in the war
на войне
Yes unfortunately there are How much
Да к сожалению есть есть Сколько
approximately Oh I don't even know if I should
приблизительно О я даже не знаю стоит ли
tell you Wow
вам говорить Во
man this is a lot as for acquaintances
человек это много как для знакомых
Yes this is a lot and Honestly I Therefore honestly I
Да это много и Честно говоря я Поэтому
want it all to
честно говоря хочу чтобы это Скорее все
end sooner because on the Ukrainian
завершилось потому что и с украинской
side the people are
стороны народ
suffering and on our side the most offensive
страдает и с нашей стороны самое обидное
thing is that people are suffering who are like ordinary people you understand But these of your acquaintances how did they even get to the war mobilization several acquaintances not friends but acquaintances who went there as volunteers specifically two people Here But these guys left precisely by mobilization That is them Well they received
мобилизации То есть их Ну им пришла
a summons they were sent there and it
повестка их отправили туда и а
turns out And what did they
получается А за что они
die for  Oh
погибли Ой
well here they say that they are fighting with the fascists there
ну тут говорят что воюют с фашистами там
they say that they are fighting with Russia that Russia
говорят что воюют с Россией что Росси
that their relatives say this is what
что ихние родственники говорят вот что
their wives mothers say this is how they are and for
ихние жёны мамы говорят вот как они за
what they died Well there are those who support
что они погибли Ну есть кто поддерживает
And there are those who are categorically against that is to say
А есть кто категорически против то есть
opinions differ There is no such thing as someone
мнения разнятся Нет такого что кто-то
directly with a flag in hand forward and there is no
прямо вот с флагом в руке вперёд и нет
such thing as someone there Let's go there
такого что кто-то там вот Давайте туда
in short here are very different people very
короче вот люди очень разные люди очень
different attitudes to this there are directly
по-разному к этому относятся есть Прямо
people who are generally categorically against
люди которые вообще категорически против
right here and there are those who really
прям вот а есть которые действительно
support Well well but this is how these
поддерживают А хорошо а вот вот как эти
people here the relatives of these deceased
люди вот родственники этих погибших
believe who is to blame for the fact that they
считают кто виноват в том что они
died I don't know I didn't talk to them on this topic
погибли Я не знаю я накли тему с ними не
if you are interested I can of
общался если вам интересно я могу
course ask then we can contact
конечно спросить потом можем связаться
if you are interested it's not that simple it
если вам интересно не это так просто
was interesting yes maybe as they say
интересно было да может как говорят
Usually when someone dies they do
Обычно когда кто-то погибает у них уж
n't ask anything because the person is
ничего не спрашивает потому что человек
there in grief like well what are you asking them What
же там в горе как бы ну что ты им Какие
questions It's cool but it turns out they
вопросы Прикольно а получается
pay for the
выплачивают за
dead probably they pay This I also
погибших наверное выплачивают Это я тоже
don't know for sure some kind of money there
не знаю наверняка какие-то уж деньги там
from the Ministry of Defense or it
от Минобороны или
goes in different ways probably  there
идут по-разному наверно
may even have been
тоже может быть даже людей были и
ideological people, that
идейные то
is, I honestly have such people.
есть я таких честно
And how do people feel about the fact that
говоря А как люди относятся к тому что
in Ami Moscow, it turns out, they sit in bars and clubs,
во Ами москви получается по барам клубам
they sit in bars and clubs, they sit everywhere. That
сидят по барам клубам сидят везде То
is, it's not only in Moscow because
есть это не только в Москве потому что я
sometimes I go to work at night and
вот иногда бывает по работе ночью езжу
look, that is, the situation is such that it's
смотрю то есть обстановка такая что
as if nothing is happening,
просто как будто бы ничего не происходит
everyone goes to bars and clubs,
по барам клубам все ходят
ASO, there is no such
АСО нет такого
thing, it turns out, about Lyuda from
что про получается Люде из
Marit to
марит в
Ot Izl now I don't know. At the beginning of the war,
от изл сейчас не знаю Вот в начале войны
indeed, when the mobilization was
действительно когда мобилизация была
going on, they
уехала были
even created these national
даже создавали вот эти вот национальные
Battalions. I know that
Батальоны вот я знаю что в Татарии
they created them in Tatarstan, in
создавали в
Bashkortostan, yes, in Bashkortostan, here on
Башкортостане Да Башкортостане вот на
Kavka, under this,
кавка под эту э
I apologize for interrupting a lot of
извиняюсь что перебиваю очень много
people when this
людей когда вот это вот
situation got heated in the second
обстановка вот накалилась в д втором
year, a lot of people while they had
году очень много людей пока была
the opportunity, that is, who rushed to Turkey,
возможность то есть кто дёрнул в Турцию
who went to the USA. That
Кто в США То
is, I also have a couple of acquaintances who
есть у меня тоже есть пара знакомых кто
left, let's say, to Turkey, they already said,
уехал допустим в Турцию они уже сказали
That's it, we are Turks, we will not return, the people
Всё мы турки мы больше не вернёмся люди
who left for the USA said, American
которые уехали в США сказали Американ
bomb,
бом
it turns out Well if there are eight dead
а получается Ну если восемь погибших ещё
then there are definitely some wounded
же тогда по-любому есть какие-то раненые
missing Well one was lying there for half a year I think that
безвести Ну один лежал полгода по-моему
is we were finding out finding out Here they
то есть мы всё узнавали узнавали Вот его
pulled him out In the end he was buried somewhere
вытащили В итоге его похоронили где-то
last month
месяц последни
Person Honestly we are still in
Человек Честно говоря мы до сих пор в
shock all because oh my God we kind of spent our whole childhood
шоке все потому что ё-моё всё детство
together such a
как бы вместе провели такая
situation someone is also there is a similar
ситуация кто-то на тоже есть похожая
story
история
Well an acquaintance as if there was Was
есть Ну знакомый как бы есть был Был
Sanya Prokhorov Well as if we with him In our
Саня Прохоров Ну как бы мы с ним По
youth we knew each other like In our youth
молодости были знакомы как По молодости
at school still in camp we were together
по школьно ещё в лагере вместе были
every year and it turns out he himself is from
каждый год и получается он сам из
Rostov and he also went his mobile Zro and I
Ростова и он тоже пошёл его мобили Зро и
don't know Or he Signed the contract mom
не знаю Или он Подписал контракт мама
never said and he also died in short
так и не сказала и он тоже погиб короче
him in general there was a video from a drone he was
его в общем там было видео с дрона его
wounded by this drone in his leg he remained
ранило этим дроном ногу ему он остался
alive but they couldn't evacuate him and they
Живой но его не могли эвакуировать и
filmed From this drone Mavic
снимали С вот этого с дрона мавика
this video was filmed very much circulated on the
снимали это видео очень гуляло по
Internet so much that his mothers
интернету сильно так аж мамам его
cried in short there are dogs in this village
плакала короче там собаки в этом селе
they are well Hungry you know because  there
они ну Голодные знаете потому что хозяев
are no owners and the dogs have gone wild and are starving, in short,
нету и собаки одичали с голодали короче
he is still half-dead.
его ещё полуживого
Well, that would be brutal. He is right there
Ну это было бы жесть он там прямо на
on the ma you can see how he twitches. He has
этом на ма видно как он дёргается он
one leg and the
одна нога у
other and they are a vile pack of dogs,
него а вторая и они подлая стая собак
about eight of them, and they are starting it from all
где-то штук восемь и начинают её со всех
sides. Half-dead Sanya Prokhorova, then
сторон полуживого Саня Прохорова то мама
his mother, in short, then his remains
его короче потом останки его
were evacuated. The remains are there. It is unclear what is
эвакуировали останки там Непонятно что
left of him. In general, they did not find him in a
от него осталось общем его нили в
closed coffin and even his mother did not
закрытом гробу и даже мама не
open it. That was it. Yes, that was how it was
открывала это было
necessary to live in Rostov, in
да это же надо было так жить в Ростове
short. Excuse me, this is a war of robots
короче Извините меня это Война роботов
against people, as
против людей как
if I were saying. It was necessary to live in Rostov so that
бы говорю Надо было жить жить в Ростове
you would be somewhere, in short, in some
чтобы тебя где-то короче в какой-то
Kherson steppe, dogs, you
степи Херсонской собаки
know, you
же знаете вы
are looking at modern
смотрите совре
cool money. Where are
г крут деньги Где крутятся
the resources spinning for this, against the background of everything
ресурсы на это на этом фоне всего того
that is happening, a very large
что происходит открылось очень большое
number of different enterprises have opened that
количество различных предприятий которые
produce weapons. Ron. These are all
производят вооружение Роны Вот это всё
small bombs, this is it. Well, in short, a
маленькие бомбочки вот это вот Ну короче
huge push. That is it. And what is the
прям огромный толчок те Вот И что самое
strangest thing again. Yes, speaking of
странное опять-таки Да вот говоря
bombs, everything is there, as if something is
бомбочки всё есть как бы что-то блин тут
wrong here.  in my opinion someone is not a doctor there
не то тут по-моему кто-то не докт
are no sanctions or is it all a dog thing you know that's
нет Или это всё собачие Понимаете вот
what I'm already leaning towards that opinion
вот я уже сейчас к такому мнению
all this in my opinion is
склоняюсь всё это по-моему
just ordinary people are being pitted
просто простых людей сталкивают лбами
against each other so that life doesn't
друг с другом чтобы жизнь мёдом не
seem like honey by the way yes you said that
казалось Кстати да вы вот это сказали
dog thing I well I didn't want to say that yes
собачий я ну я не хотел это говорить Да
there well so that it makes you sick maybe it's not
там ну чтобы это стошнить может там не
just his leg in short I won't
только ногу у него короче я не буду
voice it no I don't
озвучивать не я тоже не
like it either actually yes it's very bitter that a
люблю на самом деле Да вот очень горько
person died like that
что вот так вот человек
and I feel very sorry for the people on that side
погиб и очень жалко людей с той стороны
I know God forbid that all this ends that
знаю Дай Бог чтобы это всё завершилось
receiving your own child in a coffin is in
Что получать родного ребёнка в гробу
short God forbid yes that's
это это короче Не дай Бог
happened and how are these people who
да тако бывал а как вот эти люди которые
Well it turns out their children were taken away from them now their
Ну получается у них забрали детей теперь
coffins have been returned to them how do they feel they
им вернули гробы как они относятся они
probably still went and voted for Putin
же наверное всё равно пошли и за Путина
And you probably
А вы наверное из-за того что не живёте в
don't understand a little bit how
России немножко не понимаете как
voting
голосование
happens because you don't live in Russia Maybe I just met
происходит Может быть я просто встречал
many who are there whose
многих которые там у которых погибли
relatives died they still say yes We are
родственники они всё равно говорят да Мы
for Putin We are for Putin So well
за Путина Мы за Путина Так что
yes yes yes  By the way,
Ну да да да А кстати там вот в Мари
drones didn't reach Mari because I
беспилотники не долетали потому что я
see drones
смотрю в удмуртию
didn't reach Udmurtia
долетали удмуртию не прилетали
whoever writes this is driving, they
беспилотники тот кто это пишет гонит
only flew to Kazan and that's why they didn't
прилетали только по Казани и по этому не
fly to Vodkin,
по Водкин прилетала в
it was something else, now I'm
Удмуртии это что-то другое было Сейчас я
helping the law, it's
помо прво
interesting, while they
интересно пока
fly, in the twenty-fourth year,
долетай двад четвёртого года под атаку
Udmurtia came under attack for the first time, as
бпла впервые попала Удмуртия как сообщил
the head of the Republic, Alexander Brechalov, reported, in
глава Республики Александр бречалов
Izhevsk, there was an explosion at the Factory
ижевски произошёл взрыв на Заводском
Shop, that's where the
цехе вот се ноября был
first plant, the Izhevsk Electromechanical
первы завод Ижевский электромеханический
Plant, was in November, well, it's probably the
завод а ну это наверно
defense plant that works for the Russian Ministry of Defense,
оборон который работает на Минобороны
yes, yes, I know for sure that
России да да наве Я знаю точно что
moisture flew in last year, and Yala, yes,
прилетало в том году влагу а Яла Да
moisture, I saw a video where students are
влагу Я видел видео там где студенты
standing and shouting, somehow strangely, he flew in,
стоят кричат как-то странно он прилетел
why did they hit the dormitory? That is,
зачем они ударили по общежитию То есть
this is a dormitory 100% Why do I know because
это общежитие 100% Почему я знаю потому
Nara, I'll say, in M, the matter is because both guys are there,
Нара скажу в м дело потому с ребятами
Yes, they say, it turns out he  flies by
Да они говорят получается он летит по
coordinates by coordinates Yes, but if there is
координатам по координатам Да но если
rap interference near the place where it flies to land Yes, it turns out that the
стоит рэп помехи Да у него получается
GPS signal is lost and it deviates
сбивается сигнал GPS и он отклоняется
In a random direction it comes out
В случайном направлении выходит вот
because there is a
из-за того что там
GPS signal jammer there it is on its final
глуши сигнал GPS он на своей финальной
trajectory the last kilometers there d it
траектории последние там километра д он
turns out that it received an offset and not the workshop
получается получил смещение и не цех
hit
ударила по
the general then it turns out that the same thing
обща тогда получается тоже самое в
happened in Kazan because how many are there six or
Казани было потому что сколько там шесть
what of these planes Yes, they are generally in
что ли самолётов этих Да они вообще в
different ones there chug-chug-chug
разные там чух-чух-чух
yes So Well, that
да Так что Ну вот
means its also somehow strange Thats all in
значит как-то тоже странно Вот это всё в
Kazan there it was in a high-rise building it banged so beautifully
Казани там это в многоэтажку так красиво
there it was healthy healthy
бахнула там она здоровая здоровая
and in Saratov it was also generally
такая и в Саратове также было вообще
damn and in Saratov Yes, in Saratov there was a thirty-
блин и в Саратове Да в Саратове тридцати
seven-story building it also hit it came out
семиэтажка он тоже попала в неё вышел
about Kazan I heard for sure but there seemed to
про Казань Я слышал точно но там вроде
be no one at home and in Kazan there were two
дома никого не было и в в Казани два
drones one was then filmed by people and the
беспилотника один потом снимали люди и
second one came there at the
второй ещё пришёл туда в тот
same time yes maybe Well, theyre putting up air defense systems yes
же да может быть Ну на клепают ПВО
where to rivet already  I see
поставит уж да куда уже клепать Я смотрю
that this is every Kato processing
что вот это каждый Като перерабатывающие
plants I attack there Astrakhan Volgograd
заводы атакую там Астрахань Волгоград
Ryazan And so
Рязань И так
on maybe it's all insured and that's how
дальше может оно всё застрахованы и так
money is earned I know it's
денежки как бы зарабатываются я знаю
insured Try Stop the
застраховано Попробуй Останови
plant I know I honestly you
завод зна Я честно говоря
know some time ago I watched an
знаете какое-то время назад смотрел
American film about global
фильм американский фильм про мировой
drug trafficking say after that I understand that
наркотрафик гово я после этого Поня что
In short, all the world's
Короче все мира
Armed Forces are just one big stupid
ВС это просто один большой тупой
show just for people In short, you know
спектакль просто для людей Короче знаете
and then they start playing on
а там уже дальше начинают играть на
patriotism on this whole topic
патриотизме на всей вот этой вот теме
So I honestly it seems to me that everything
Так что я честно говоря мне кажется всё
again it seems to me that we need to look
опять-таки мне кажется надо смотреть
where the money is flowing
куда текут
Cool Well in fact Nothing
Прикольно Ну на самом деле Ничего
cool about the death of people there
прикольного смерть людей этом хорошего
is nothing good in this Unfortunately
нету К сожалению
somehow like that somehow like that And you only
вот как-то так как-то так А вы только
talk about war yes Well I talk about different things
про войну общаетесь да Ну я про разное
I am generally an anthropologist I am looking for people
общаюсь Я вообще антрополог я ищу людей
with whom to talk about anthropology but there are
с которыми об антропологии поговорить но
few of them here so it turns out about
тут таких мало поэтому получается о
politics And I mainly talk about religion
политике А я в основном про религию
I am just still studying religion
разговариваю я просто религию ещё изучаю
And what are you by faith
А кто вы по веро исповедания
deist deist  deist
деист деист деист
A deist is someone who believes in God a
А деист это который верит в бога
person who believes in God but does not
человек который верит в бога но не
adhere to any religion
придерживается какой-то никакой религии
Well yes about the patri like this is the God of the Polani
Ну да про патри про типа это Бог полани
yes
да
Yes honestly of course I
Да честно я конечно вас как еврея ни в
don't want to offend you as a Jew in any way but I am not a
коем случае не хочу обидеть но я я не
religious Jew And that's it Well then you
религиозный еврей А всё Ну тогда вы меня
understand me perfectly well I am secular I do
тоже понимаете прекрасно я я светский я
not profess the Mari faith I do
не марийские верования не исповедую
not profess the Jewish faith
иудейские верования не
I was born in the Soviet Union in
исповедую я родился в советском созе в
1981 in a secular
восемьдесят первом году в светском
state Well like
государстве Ну как бы
Yeah therefore Well you know also somehow it all
Ага поэтому Ну знаете тоже както это всё
smacks of untruth to put it mildly
попахивает как бы неправдой мягко говоря
yes all religions are God but he is not like they
да все религии это Бог но он не такой
say about him in it
рассказывается
I say more than that Yes to me It
говор я больше того говорю Да мне Мне
seems to me the real true God
кажется настоящего истинного Бога
who was before Yes even in the times of
который был раньше Да ещё во времена
Sumer in Babylonia yes they just specifically
шумера в вавилонии да как раз специально
hide them from
прячут От
people They came up with fairy tales for them
людей придумали им сказочки
yes perhaps this option is because
да возможно и такой вариант потому что
Honestly I have seen what religions do
Честно говоря я видел что религии делают
to people Lord my God Sometimes it
с людьми Господи боже мой Иногда мне
seems to me that Evolution has not reached everyone
кажется что Эволюция На не до всех дошла
Honestly I am of course not a supporter of
Честно говоря я конечно не сторонник
evolution either yes
эволюции тоже да
[laughter]
[смех]
but Well yes  especially since I see how you
но Ну да тем более я смотрю как вот
know the Russian Orthodox Church says
знаете ру православная церковь говорят
there is humility There and so on and
там смирение Там и так дальше а сами
Patriarch Kirill himself rides a Merci In short,
Патриарх Кирилл ездит на мерси Короче
all in gold Yes, everyone look where the
весь в золоте Да все смотрите куда текут
money is flowing from my personal experience the truth is
деньги по моему личному опыту правда
only that this world
только состоит в том что этот мир
belongs to the strong and the smart, so if you are
принадлежит сильным и умным вот если ты
stupid and also weak then you are like
тупой ещ и слабый то ты
two Strong guys understand
ког двое Крепких ребят разбирается вот
this in my opinion
такого я мнени
in short it is better to put
короче лучше поставить
aside you are from Israel yes yes from
сторонки вы вы же из Израиля да да из
Haifa Yes I once studied the armies of the world
Хайф Да я в одно время изучал армии мира
yes and I know what the
да и я вот знаю что из себя представляе
IDF is Well, really a very
цахал это Ну действительно очень
developed military
развитая военная
structure for me honestly it was
структура для меня честно говоря было
a shock how could what happened on October 7th
шоком как 7 октября могло произойти вот
happen here is your opinion what
то что произошло вот ваше мнение како да
yes The fact is that our intelligence
э Дело в том что наши разведывательные
services underestimated the enemy
службы недооценили э противника
underestimated his preparation for such a
недооценили подготовку его к такой
daring operation no one could
дерзкой операции никто не мог
believe I was simply amazed that I
поверить меня просто поразило то что я
was in Israel I just saw this wall
был в Израиле Я видел просто эту стену
you know I was simply surprised how they
знаете меня просто удивило как они
were able to get to it
смогли к ней подобраться
well there in the end there are cameras There I
вот ну там в конце концов камеры Там я
even saw these
видел даже вот эти вот
machine guns you know on  which have a
пулемёты знаете на которых вот
video camera installed on the side And
установлена сбоку такая видеокамера И
on top there is another one like this Well, that is, they Yes
сверху ещё такой этот ну то есть они да
If you saw the video They
Если вы видели ролик они с дрона с дрона
dropped a bomb from a drone onto these machine guns and
бомбочку на такие пулемёты скидывали и
disabled them Well, again, how did the
выводили их из строя Ну вот опять-таки а
drone get there Lord,
как Дрон туда смог подобраться Господи
that's how Well, that's how I think that
вот как ну вот как я думаю что там
Russia was involved Russia was helping
Россия замешана была Россия помогала
Hamas But how, that is, I
хамасу а вот Каким образом то есть вот я
also heard this theory But how, how
тоже эту теорию слышал А вот Каким
Yes, look Russia, together with
образом как Да смотрите Россия вместе с
Iran, supplied Hamas with weapons and
Ираном поставляла хамасу оружия
instructors Yes, there were Russian
инструкторов Да там сидели российские
Generals sitting there They were in charge too In Gaza, maybe, uh, you
Генералы управляли тож в газе может ээ
heard,
слышали
uh, after the Israeli airstrikes,
ээ после израильских авиаударов был убит
Russian General
российский генерал
Lokonkov Kolokolnikov was killed I don't remember What is the name
локон ков Колокольников не помню Как имя
and the Russian General Gruzd In
зовут и российский генерал Грузд вот в
Gaza, officially - Russian Yes, the
газе официально - Российская Да
Russian department officially
российское ведомство официально ихние
evacuated their bodies Then the dead Yes,
тела ээ эвакуировал потом мёртвых Да
through the humanitarian corridor they requested
через ээ запросили коридор у
through it through the Red
гуманитарный через он через Красный
Cross, their bodies were taken out and well, somewhere
Крест ихние вывезли тела и ну куда-то их
in Syria, then they were transported to Tartus And
в Сирию тогда в Тартус переправили А
from there they were already on board to Russia This is
оттуда уже бортом на Россию это Есть
something  here
такое вот
they were leading the operation of the
и они руководили операцией
Hamas attack on
нападения Хамаса на
Israel Russia or what Well Russian
Израиль Россия что ли Ну российские
Generals together with Iranian Yes to the SIRS
Генералы вместе с ирански Да к сиров
themselves Yes they developed the instructions completely
сами они Да инструктировать полностью
I don't believe that the KSIR has such
разрабатывали Я не верю что у ксир такие
long arms My God they
длинные руки Господи они себя прокси
surrounded themselves with these proxies Are they really capable of
этими обложили Неужели они способны на
such a special operation right now now
такую спецоперацию вот сейчас сейчас
now when for example our Israeli special services
сейчас когда например наши спецслужбы
liquidated almost the entire
израильские ликвидировали почти всю
top and active members of the Hizballah
верхушку и актив хиз балы пейджера
they saw a pager a pager it's just a bomb here in
видели пейджера это просто бомбе у нас в
Israel it was like that I'm not a believer Yes but
Израиле прям было то я не верующий Да но
I kind of went to the synagogue on Shabbat and
я как бы в Шаббат пошёл типа в синагогу
even stood there like well for the sake of this
даже аж пря постоял типа ну ради такого
This with a pager It's just fantastic if they
Это с пейджером Это просто фантастика
told me that I wouldn't believe it
мне бы так рассказали Я бы не поверил
if I didn't
если бы не знал так что
know so Yes I don't know Really Russia has such
Да не знаю Неужели у России такие
long arms Why then Why does Russia
длинные А зачем тогда А зачем России вот
need this look Russia is like Iran it
это вот надо смотрите Россия как Иран
wants
она хочет
destabilization of the Middle East
дестабилизации Ближнего Востока
destabilization of Europe destabilization of
дестабилизации Европы дестабилизации
Central Asia so
Средней Азии для того
that the world community distracts from
чтобы мировое сообщество Отвлечь от
the attack on Ukraine yes that is because
нападения на Украину да то есть из-за
the attack has begun  Hamas to
того что начался нападение Хамаса на
Israel yes The world focus of the world media
Израиль да Мировой фокус мировых СМИ
immediately switched from the conflict in
сразу переключился из конфликта в
Ukraine yes to the east everything was
Украине да на восток всё тогда там
cruel then these shots were specially
жестокие эти кадры специально были Так
So it's
что вот
so very interesting I'll look at
так очень интересно я посмотрю про
these Of course I heard something like that there was
этих Слышал конечно что-то такое есть
an interest in I'm just saying
интересовался ко Я говорю просто меня
this struck me how they could
вот это вот поразило как могли
get close to the challah So quietly That is to say I
подобраться к халу Так тихо То есть это
know this straight I just remember the story of the
пря знаю просто я помню историю о войне
Yom Kippur War when in s days Excuse
Судного дня когда за сть дней Извините
me they gave it to everyone around I for God's sake
меня дали всем вокруг Я ради Бога
Forgive me for my French yes and
Простите меня за мой французский да и
here's the situation then how
вот такая вот ситуация то потом как
Masad worked for example after the
работал массад по допустим вот после
Olympics yes that is how they
Олимпиады да то есть как они всех
drank everyone yes And this story from the pager
выпи да И вот эта вот история с пейджера
yes that is Well this is really just
да то есть Ну это же действительно
beauty yes And here nearby and like this that
красота просто да А тут под боком и вот
is just I also saw these
так вот то есть просто я тоже видел эти
shots from the festival this is complete madness
кадры с фестиваля это полная жесть
in general it's horror yes Horror they shot in short
вообще это ужас да Ужас стреляли короче
at a man who was just running you can see
в человека который просто бежит видно
that he has no weapons or anything and in
что у него ни оружия ничего нет и ему
short they just shoot him in the back he
короче прям просто в спину стреляет он
falls and you know what sa what's the most cynical thing the
падает и знаете что са что самое цинично
whole world saw this and after that Russia
это видел весь мир и после этого Россия
takes the official delegation of Hamas
берёт официальную делегацию Хамаса у
as guests of honor
себя принимает как почётных
And you don't know this They are on the list of
гостей А вы не знаете этот Они в списке
terrorists of Russia well already Taliban in
террористов России ну уже Талибан в
Russia was excluded from the list of
России исключили из списка
terrorists not that I heard interesting
террористов не это я слышал интересно
or
или
from carried on the list of
из носили в список
terrorists surprising yes yes that's what I'm saying
террористов удивительно да да вот говорю
I just every day I realize that
я просто вот с каждым днём я понимаю что
I don't understand anything at all
я вообще в чём не разбираюсь
and in short a
и короче
nightmare I understood Okay All the best to you
кошмар понял Хорошо Всего вам хорошего
great talk everything Let everything be
классно поговорили всё Пусть всё будет
Yes be
Да будьте
healthy so Today I was half and
здоровы так Сегодня я был наполовину на
half
половину
Jewish So well subscribe to this channel
еврей Так а ну подпишитесь на этот канал
and I will
и будет
like like your father and
лайки сделайте лайки отцу ан
drone subscription Look Or you are not
дрони подписочка Посмотрите Или вы не
subscribed if you are not subscribed
подписаны если не подписаны
subscribe And after that Like
подпишитесь А после этого Поставьте лайк
and Leave a
и Оставьте
comment like subscription komen Glory to
комментарий лайк подписка комен Слава
Ukraine
Украине
letter on y Instagram I don't know why
пись на й Instagram Я не знаю для чого
this is for what there to watch on Of And
це то для чого то там дивитись на Оф А
for you ond or three clicks But you trim
для тебе онд або три клика Але ты тримае
me and I will be in me there are a bunch of fouls and in
мене и я буду в мене там Купа фолов и в
me there will be  cool setting to do but
мене буде класний настр щоб робити но
cool video write on y instag Popik Andr
крут вдео пись на й instag Попик Андр
Here come on I'm waiting
Вот давай я чекаю
V
V